#### VIGNESH.U

Mobile: 91-9600028483, Email: vignesh.uthandi@gmail.com/vignesh\_mapy@yahoo.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Competent and versatile professional offering a comprehensive experience of over 12+ years. 5 years in BPO, 7+years in US IT Staffing & Business Development.

Good understanding of the business processes involved in the discrete Contingent Staffing verticals, essential to connect and engage in a meaningful dialogue with the client with an ability to quickly understand business challenges and recommend relevant solutions.

Good understanding of New Proposal Development, Bidding, Account Management, Hunting and Harvesting of business required by clients to run their business operations.

Enough experience in US market for starting new business and acquiring new accounts.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# INTROLLIGENT INC Delivery Head Solutions

Sept 2019 - Present

- Review and update operational policies and procedures to optimize operational efficiency
- Excellent problem resolution, judgment, negotiating and decision making skills
- Drive the team to continuous metric-driven process improvement, including defining new metrics where appropriate
- Direct and manage Off-Shore recruitment process (RPO). Spearheaded strategy, planning and communication.
- Ensured delivery for Recruitment process, as well as standards of service (quality, effectiveness, productivity, efficiency etc.) to agreed SLA's on a daily basis
- Shared understanding of client's recurring needs, hiring patterns, key skills/traits and develop a strategic sourcing plan
- Evaluated direct reports. Trained team members to acquire necessary skills and performance attributes, in line with business and personal development needs.
- Conduct performance review and career development discussions, reward employees, acquire new talent, drive my team towards common goals and motivate my teamssee less

# VIVA USA INC Business Development Manager

Oct 2016 - Sept 2019

- Develop and generate new business opportunities by locating, developing, defining, negotiating, and closing business.
- Developing relationships with potential clients, MSP/VMS, & State Govt clients.
- Managed IT Purchasing / Requisition processes.
- Have closed and negotiated IT Contracts for more than 1 year.
- Vendor Management.
- Managed Administrate Staff around IT Purchasing.
- Strong Expertise in IT Procurement.
- Creating database, outbound sales calls, networking, meetings, and client visits.
- Identify business opportunities for Temp staffing with clients in areas of IT, Engineering and Non-IT.
- IT Product Sales, Software Sales & Proposal Writing.
- Prepare Presentation for various platforms Product Notes and Sales Pitches.
- Maintain relationships with clients/hiring mangers so as to receive ongoing requirements.
- Responsible for new business development, account management and operations for US Market.
- Research on potential tie-ups for Business Development Market Sizing research, identifying potential new tie-up opportunities.
- Analyze market trends to potential opportunities and participate in market research.
- Extensive research on Target companies, Prospective Clients and Decision makers.
- Generating leads and follow-up.

- Perform cold calling and generate new business.
- Worked as a presales manager to understand client requirements, define Business Solution, responding to various RFI/RFP for different clients which led to winning bids for the organization.
- Serve as a single point of contact for all the Proposal development activities for India & US
- Analyzing all RFP/RFQ/RFI requirements and develop internal response plans and schedules to meet customer proposal/quotation requirements.
- Develop proposal response templates in compliance with client requirements as well as internal branding guidelines.
- Led a content marketing initiative and created multiple brochures, case studies, blogs and other digital content for Company's
  website.
- Expertise in identifying customer requirements as drafted in RFP, scripting proposals & to into the solution
- Adept in analyzing information system needs, evaluating end-user requirements and analyzing design solutions as per need of RFP/RFI/RFQ.

Aegis Pvt Ltd Jun 13, 2015- Oct- 2016

# Client: Reliance Relationship Manager

- Works closely with new business development staff, actively participates in the development of new business from existing or prospective Institutional clients.
- Helping clients with their account details, giving advice on financial investments.
- To cater individual clients while trying to generate new business and clients for the bank.
- Supervise other bank employees who communicate with clients, like loan officers.
- Sound financial knowledge as well as thorough information about company's various offerings to identify the need of the
  customer and advice him accordingly.
- Understanding of banking regulations, latest products and services, specific markets related to the clients handling.
- Understanding and interest in financial / banking products and markets
- Provide all types to support to distributors in terms of product information, training, new fund offers.
- Maintaining healthy relationship with major distributors and channel partners.
- Developing and maintaining relationships as a strategic partner with clients by promoting and delivering a broad range of products and services with the primary focus on value-added sales and revenue growth.
- Planning, formulating and implementing promotional strategies to increase market penetration and visibility.
- Maintaining up to date knowledge and understanding of products, processes, and relevant legal, regulatory and technology requirements through audits and quality checks, to ensure decisions are adequately documented, and clearly communicated.

Infomatics, Inc Jan 2015 – June 2015

#### Sr. Technical Recruiter

#### Lead a team of 2 Recruiters

- Involved in Full Cycle Technical Recruitment involving sourcing, identifying, interviewing, screening, formatting and placing personnel in quick turnaround time in contract, contract-to-hire in the Information Technology industry throughout the United States.
- Maintaining a strong vendor network across the US for contractual assignments.
- Coordinating with Account Managers to fully understand client requirements
- Allocating requirements on priority basis to team members and working on high priority requirements
- Online searches / Job postings / Referrals
- Involved in H1B transfer and H1 sponsoring procedures
- Proactively building up database based on prospective direct client requirement
- Involved in salary negotiations and to ensure delivery of consultants confirmed on projects.
- Responsible for increasing number of qualified applicants in database.
- Source candidates using traditional and creative sourcing methods, including but not limited to referrals, networking, internal database searches, online searches, Internet postings, referrals, and user/technical groups.
- Screening & short listing the profiles based on requirements.

#### PERI Software Solutions Pvt Ltd, Chennai

May 2013- Sep 2014

#### **IT RECRUITER**

- Understanding overall needs and requirements
- Creating comprehensive job description based on hiring specifications.
- Working along with Sourcing Analyst to develop appropriate sourcing strategies for each role.
- Developing and managing strong consultative relationships with hiring managers and candidates.
- Solicitation and documenting hiring manager and candidate feedback throughout the interview process.
- Disposition all candidates personally contacted in the recruitment cycle.
- Physical check of each of the candidate profile, qualifications, skills and experience.
- Screening candidates according to the company requirement.

- Explaining about the job roles and responsibilities.
- Explaining about the company philosophy and values they follow.
- Explaining about the place of work and salary package which applies to the role.
- Explaining about the training offered and probationary period and protocols.
- Explaining about employee benefits and facilities according to the role and place.
- Company confidential information and follow the rules to protect according to company guidelines under government law procedures.
- Participated in recruitment knowledge sharing and best practices.
- Managing the recruiting process to meet hiring goals through the use of effective resource management.
- Consistently meeting the performance metrics.
- Providing reports and regular status updates.
- Solicit referrals from potential talent and internal employees recently hired.
- Knowledge in US IT Requirement, Head Hunting Strategies, Interviewing and Negotiations.
- Knowledge in US Work Permits & Visa types (CPT, OPT, H1, L1, H1 Transfers, GC & EAD)
- Knowledge in US Job portals (Dice, Tech Fetch, Career Centre & Monster)
- Knowledge in C2C (Corp to Corp), W2 and 1099.
- Knowledge in US Tax Terms Corp 1099 W2 forms

# IV SUPPORT TECHNOLOGIES, Chennai

July 2012– Feb 2013

# **QUALITY SUPERVISOR**

# Lead a team of 5 QAs'

- Coordination of all Data Management Activities
- Review and provide inputs to study/project documents
- Ensure timely and high quality delivery of data management deliverables
- Provide status reports to the client, internal management as required
- Support QC/QA processes of the program.
- Provide input to resources, timelines as required.
- Mentor the team and provide guidance for assigned work; review in detail and analyze the work done and give feedback based on their performances.
- People management and resource/work allocation.
- Lead discussions of process requirements and planning
- Ensure process milestones are met according to agreed quality.
- Provide inputs to process strategy.
- Act as primary contact for all process management problems, issues and questions from study teams and be responsible for issues resolutions.
- Provide regular feedback to direct reports and perform RCA (Root Cause Analysis).

# SUTHERLAND GLOBAL SERVICE PVT LTD, Chennai QUALITY ANALYST

Jun 2010- Jul 2012

- Functioning as Quality Analyst responsible for identifying errors and perform corrective actions. Handled over 5 projects in diverse technical and customer service projects.
- Development of components of the Quality Management Plan such as Quality Validation Specifications and Database Structure Document and ensure process flow from start-up.
- Designing the Project Management Plan, defining timelines.
- Training to the personnel on Process Flow, Standard Operating Procedures, Documents, Templates, Forms as well as Project specific trainings on protocol.
- Maintain a working knowledge of program and assure compliance with, applicable Quality guidelines and good standard operating procedures.
- FMEA ANALYSIS (FAILURE MODE EFFECTIVE ANALYSIS) performed to analyze the defect trend in the respective programs and corrective action plan to curb the defect ratio and maintain Quality metrics and standards are achieved.
- Ensure regular dip-stick is conducted for any process updates and review to ensure it is followed within the given deadline for all process related queries and updates.
- Ensuring that all the Quality Control measures are carried out and the quality checks are conducted regularly prior any fatal instances.

# INFOTRONICS PVT LTD, Chennai CUSTOMER SUPPORT OFFICER

2<u>009-2010</u>

- Generating Leads for a UK based program for insulating properties.
- Review the leads created and ensure it is validated and clearly documented.
- Ensuring the target is met on regular basis and consistently working towards team target achievements.

# **CUSTOMER SUPPORT OFFICER**

- Generating Leads for a US based program (DIRECT SURVEY USA) for diabetic patients for the diabetic company to sell
  diabetic testing supplies for the lead.
- Review the leads created and ensure it is validated and clearly documented.
- Ensuring the target is met on regular basis and consistently working towards team target achievements.

# PROFESSIONAL SKILL SETS AND CERTIFICATES

- NISM CERTIFIED
- SIX SIGMA GREEN BELT TRAINED
- MS OFFICE, EXCEL,
- POWER POINT AND PPT Presentations
- Graphs and Charts for Data Projection
- ISO Guidelines
- USA Tax Terms C2C W2 109
- USA Work Permits & Visa Types (CPT, OPT, H1, L1, H1 Transfers, GC & EAD)
- RFP RFI Market Research Presales Digital Marketing Analytics Email Marketing Product Management Lead Generation

# **EDUCATION**

**BA ENGLISH LITERATURE - 2008** 

ANNAMALAI UNIVERSITY